{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "The human eye forms the image of an object at its:",
      "op_1": "Cornea",
      "op_2": "Iris",
      "op_3": "Pupil",
      "op_4": "Retina",
      "ans": "Retina"
    },
    {
      "question": "The least distance of distinct vision for a young adult with normal vision is about:",
      "op_1": "25 m",
      "op_2": "2.5 cm",
      "op_3": "25 cm",
      "op_4": "2.5 m",
      "ans": "25 cm"
    },
    {
      "question": "The change in focal length of an eye lens is caused by the action of the:",
      "op_1": "Pupil",
      "op_2": "Retina",
      "op_3": "Ciliary muscles",
      "op_4": "Iris",
      "ans": "Ciliary muscles"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which part of the eye controls the amount of light entering the eye?",
      "op_1": "Cornea",
      "op_2": "Lens",
      "op_3": "Iris",
      "op_4": "Retina",
      "ans": "Iris"
    },
    {
      "question": "The phenomenon of splitting of white light into its constituent colors is called:",
      "op_1": "Reflection",
      "op_2": "Refraction",
      "op_3": "Dispersion",
      "op_4": "Scattering",
      "ans": "Dispersion"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following eye defects can be corrected using a concave lens?",
      "op_1": "Hypermetropia",
      "op_2": "Presbyopia",
      "op_3": "Myopia",
      "op_4": "Cataract",
      "ans": "Myopia"
    },
    {
      "question": "The coloured part of the eye is called:",
      "op_1": "Cornea",
      "op_2": "Retina",
      "op_3": "Iris",
      "op_4": "Pupil",
      "ans": "Iris"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a defect of vision?",
      "op_1": "Myopia",
      "op_2": "Hypermetropia",
      "op_3": "Presbyopia",
      "op_4": "Accommodation",
      "ans": "Accommodation"
    },
    {
      "question": "The light-sensitive cells in the retina are called:",
      "op_1": "Rods and cones",
      "op_2": "Ciliary muscles",
      "op_3": "Optic nerves",
      "op_4": "Iris muscles",
      "ans": "Rods and cones"
    },
    {
      "question": "The persistence of vision for human eye is approximately:",
      "op_1": "1/10th of a second",
      "op_2": "1/16th of a second",
      "op_3": "1/20th of a second",
      "op_4": "1/25th of a second",
      "ans": "1/16th of a second"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which part of the eye is responsible for its characteristic color?",
      "op_1": "Cornea",
      "op_2": "Iris",
      "op_3": "Pupil",
      "op_4": "Retina",
      "ans": "Iris"
    },
    {
      "question": "The ability of the eye lens to adjust its focal length is called:",
      "op_1": "Adaptation",
      "op_2": "Accommodation",
      "op_3": "Regulation",
      "op_4": "Adjustment",
      "ans": "Accommodation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following colors deviates the most when passing through a prism?",
      "op_1": "Red",
      "op_2": "Yellow",
      "op_3": "Green",
      "op_4": "Violet",
      "ans": "Violet"
    },
    {
      "question": "The defect of vision in which a person cannot see distant objects clearly is called:",
      "op_1": "Hypermetropia",
      "op_2": "Presbyopia",
      "op_3": "Myopia",
      "op_4": "Astigmatism",
      "ans": "Myopia"
    },
    {
      "question": "The part of the eye that regulates the amount of light entering is called:",
      "op_1": "Retina",
      "op_2": "Iris",
      "op_3": "Cornea",
      "op_4": "Lens",
      "ans": "Iris"
    }
  ]
}